the mayhem in market has left very few
stocks untouched however the good thing
is that even the high quality companies
which promise considerably high safety
are down and trading at historically low
valuations in our ideas for profit today
I will be discussing about one such
stock which warrants investors attention
power grid the defensive nature of this
business will be a boon amid the market
volatility that we are witnessing
moreover the company is also relatively
insulated from the shocks of coronavirus
and yet is trading at attractive
valuations right now now this highly
defensive business is available at eight
times it's Fi twenty-one estimated
earnings which is definitely at the
lowest level seen historically moreover
at the current market price it is also
offering a dividend yield of close to
seven percent which is good considering
the stability in the business and also
the consistent cash flows that the
company enjoys Street also has very low
expectations from power grid considering
the peaking capex in transmission and
power while this means that the earnings
growth would not be very high or
encouraging on the other hand it's still
there there are still enough reasons to
believe that the company could report
about eight to ten percent annual growth
in the next one to two years now the
company needs stable growth in capital
to increase the revenues now even if the
capex could be muted this year at about
fifteen thousand crore rupees the
company is expected to commissioned
projects worth about twenty thousand
crore rupees in this fiscal compared to
about nineteen thousand crore rupees
they are seen the last year now there
are opportunities in transmission as
well so far in the current fiscal the
company has acquired projects worth
about ten thousand crore rupees with all
India market share of about fifty to
fifty five percent now it is expected
that the projects worth about thirty
three thousand crores
I get to be awarded before the end of
fiscal year 2021 moreover these projects
could also be more emanated because of
the competitive bidding where power grid
has caused and all
the funding now also the company is
looking for monetizing assets and has
received a mandate to raise our funds
worth about ten thousand crore rupees
through the in bits secondly the recent
reduction in the overall interest rate
is definitely good news for power grid
the company can raise funds at
relatively low rates for the upcoming
projects and also get the benefit in
case of debt which is maturing to sum up
while the growth in earnings could be
slow but because of the consistency in
growth positive cash flows regulated
businesses and high dividend dividend
yield Power Grid correctly provides
safety in the volatile market conditions
right now now it is a relatively safer
bet for people and yet deliver decent
returns
whenever the recovery also takes place
going ahead from here
[Music]